[
  {
    "question": "The Lord prepares a way to obey His commandments\n",
    "book": "BofM\n",
    "answer": "1 Nephi 3:7\n\n1 Nephite \n\n3 rings on plates\n\nThe Lord prepared a way to get those plates\n\n7 And it came to pass that I, Nephi, said unto my father: I will go and do the things which the Lord hath commanded, for I know that the Lord giveth no commandments unto the children of men, save he shall prepare a way for them that they may accomplish the thing which he commandeth them.\n",
    "category": "Commandments\n",
    "id": 1
  },
  {
    "question": "Adam fell that men might be",
    "book": "BofM",
    "answer": "2 Nephi 2:22-25\n\n2 Nephites grateful for the fall\n\nThey, like Adam and Eve took 2 bites\n\n22 And now, behold, if Adam had not transgressed he would not have fallen, but he would have remained in the garden of Eden. And all things which were created must have remained in the same state in which they were after they were created; and they must have remained forever, and had no end.\n\n23 And they would have had no children; wherefore they would have remained in a state of innocence, having no joy, for they knew no misery; doing no good, for they knew no sin.\n\n24 But behold, all things have been done in the wisdom of him who knoweth all things.\n\n25 Adam fell that men might be; and men are, that they might have joy.",
    "category": "The Plan of Salvation",
    "id": 2
  },
  {
    "question": "We are free to choose liberty or captivity",
    "book": "BofM",
    "answer": "2 Nephi 2:27\n\n2 Nephites with 2 choices are free 2 choose liberty or captivity\n\n27 Wherefore, men are free according to the flesh; and all things are given them which are expedient unto man. And they are free to choose liberty and eternal life, through the great Mediator of all men, or to choose captivity and death, according to the captivity and power of the devil; for he seeketh that all men might be miserable like unto himself.",
    "category": "The Plan of Salvation",
    "id": 3
  },
  {
    "question": "All are alike unto God",
    "book": "BofM",
    "answer": "2 Nephi 26:33\n\n2 Nephites are happy to know that all the people in the numbers are alike UN2 God\n\n33 For none of these iniquities come of the Lord; for he doeth that which is good among the children of men; and he doeth nothing save it be plain unto the children of men; and he inviteth them all to come unto him and partake of his goodness; and he denieth none that come unto him, black and white, bond and free, male and female; and he remembereth the heathen; and all are alike unto God, both Jew and Gentile.",
    "category": "The Godhead",
    "id": 4
  },
  {
    "question": "God gives knowledge line upon line.",
    "book": "BofM",
    "answer": "2 Nephi 28:30\n\n2 Nephits\n\nGod giving 28 lines of revelation (knowledge)\n\n30 For behold, thus saith the Lord God: I will give unto the children of men line upon line, precept upon precept, here a little and there a little; and blessed are those who hearken unto my precepts, and lend an ear unto my counsel, for they shall learn wisdom; for unto him that receiveth I will give more; and from them that shall say, We have enough, from them shall be taken away even that which they have.",
    "category": "Acquiring Spiritual Knowledge",
    "id": 5
  },
  {
    "question": "If we feast upon the words of Christ, we can know all things that we should do",
    "book": "BofM",
    "answer": "2 Nephi 32:3\n\n2 Nephites feasting upon the word with 32 oz slurpee\n\n3 Angels speak by the power of the Holy Ghost; wherefore, they speak the words of Christ. Wherefore, I said unto you, feast upon the words of Christ; for behold, the words of Christ will tell you all things what ye should do.",
    "category": "Acquiring Spiritual Knowledge",
    "id": 6
  },
  {
    "question": "If we pray always, God will consecrate our performance for the welfare of our souls.",
    "book": "BofM",
    "answer": "2 Nephi 32:8-9\n\n2 Nephites praying so that God will consecrate their drinking a 32 oz slurpee\n\n8 And now, my beloved brethren, I perceive that ye ponder still in your hearts; and it grieveth me that I must speak concerning this thing. For if ye would hearken unto the Spirit which teacheth a man to pray ye would know that ye must pray; for the evil spirit teacheth not a man to pray, but teacheth him that he must not pray.\n\n9 But behold, I say unto you that ye must pray always, and not faint; that ye must not perform any thing unto the Lord save in the first place ye shall pray unto the Father in the name of Christ, that he will consecrate thy performance unto thee, that thy performance may be for the welfare of thy soul.",
    "category": "Acquiring Spiritual Knowledge",
    "id": 7
  },
  {
    "question": "By serving others we serve God",
    "book": "BofM",
    "answer": "Mosiah 2:17\n\nNose Eye A for Mosiah\n\nTwo goblets for 2\n\nServe God (one goblet) and others (the other goblet)\n\n17 And behold, I tell you these things that ye may learn wisdom; that ye may learn that when ye are in the service of your fellow beings ye are only in the service of your God.",
    "category": "Commandments",
    "id": 8
  },
  {
    "question": "Obedience brings blessings and happiness.",
    "book": "BofM",
    "answer": "Mosiah 2:41\n\nNose Eye A for Mosiah\n\n2 hands on his head for 2\n\nHe's happy because he's keeping the commandments\n\n41 And moreover, I would desire that ye should consider on the blessed and happy state of those that keep the commandments of God. For behold, they are blessed in all things, both temporal and spiritual; and if they hold out faithful to the end they are received into heaven, that thereby they may dwell with God in a state of never-ending happiness. O remember, remember that these things are true; for the Lord God hath spoken it.",
    "category": "Commandments",
    "id": 9
  },
  {
    "question": "Put off the natural man and become a Saint through the Atonement.",
    "book": "BofM",
    "answer": "Mosiah 3:19\n\nNose Eye A (Mosiah) \n\n3 rings for 3\n\nNatural (angry) man\n\n19 For the natural man is an enemy to God, and has been from the fall of Adam, and will be, forever and ever, unless he yields to the enticings of the Holy Spirit, and putteth off the natural man and becometh a saint through the atonement of Christ the Lord, and becometh as a child, submissive, meek, humble, patient, full of love, willing to submit to all things which the Lord seeth fit to inflict upon him, even as a child doth submit to his father.",
    "category": "The Atonement of Jesus Christ",
    "id": 10
  },
  {
    "question": "Believe in God and that He has all wisdom",
    "book": "BofM",
    "answer": "Mosiah 4:9\n\nBig Nose Eye for Mosiah\n\nBee-leaf in God that He has all wisdom\n\nOn a 4 leaf clover for 4\n\n9 Believe in God; believe that he is, and that he created all things, both in heaven and in earth; believe that he has all wisdom, and all power, both in heaven and in earth; believe that man doth not comprehend all the things which the Lord can comprehend.",
    "category": "Acquiring Spiritual Knowledge",
    "id": 11
  },
  {
    "question": "Through baptism we enter a covenant with God",
    "book": "BofM",
    "answer": "Mosiah 18:8-10\n\nNose eye a for Mosiah\n\n18 year-old missionary for 18\n\n8 And it came to pass that he said unto them: Behold, here are the waters of Mormon (for thus were they called) and now, as ye are desirous to come into the fold of God, and to be called his people, and are willing to bear one another's burdens, that they may be light;\n\n9 Yea, and are willing to mourn with those that mourn; yea, and comfort those that stand in need of comfort, and to stand as witnesses of God at all times and in all things, and in all places that ye may be in, even until death, that ye may be redeemed of God, and be numbered with those of the first resurrection, that ye may have eternal life-\n\n10 Now I say unto you, if this be the desire of your hearts, what have you against being baptized in the name of the Lord, as a witness before him that ye have entered into a covenant with him, that ye will serve him and keep his commandments, that he may pour out his Spirit more abundantly upon you?",
    "category": "Ordinances and Covenants",
    "id": 12
  },
  {
    "question": "Jesus Christ experienced our pains and overcame sin and death",
    "book": "BofM",
    "answer": "Alma 7:11-13\n\nBird is an owl for Owlma\n\nChrist suffered the 7 listed afflictions\n\n11 And he shall go forth, suffering pains and afflictions and temptations of every kind; and this that the word might be fulfilled which saith he will take upon him the pains and the sicknesses of his people.\n\n12 And he will take upon him death, that he may loose the bands of death which bind his people; and he will take upon him their infirmities, that his bowels may be filled with mercy, according to the flesh, that he may know according to the flesh how to succor his people according to their infirmities.\n\n13 Now the Spirit knoweth all things; nevertheless the Son of God suffereth according to the flesh that he might take upon him the sins of his people, that he might blot out their transgressions according to the power of his deliverance; and now behold, this is the testimony which is in me.",
    "category": "The Atonement of Jesus Christ",
    "id": 13
  },
  {
    "question": "There must be an Atonement made.",
    "book": "BofM",
    "answer": "Alma 34:9-10\n\nBird is an owl for Owlma\n\nChrist's suffered atonement in His 34th year\n\nRoman Numeral 34 on rock\n\n9 For it is expedient that an atonement should be made; for according to the great plan of the Eternal God there must be an atonement made, or else all mankind must unavoidably perish; yea, all are hardened; yea, all are fallen and are lost, and must perish except it be through the atonement which it is expedient should be made.\n\n10 For it is expedient that there should be a great and last sacrifice; yea, not a sacrifice of man, neither of beast, neither of any manner of fowl; for it shall not be a human sacrifice; but it must be an infinite and eternal sacrifice.",
    "category": "The Atonement of Jesus Christ",
    "id": 14
  },
  {
    "question": "Go no more after the lust of your eyes",
    "book": "BofM",
    "answer": "Alma 39:9\n\nOwl for Owlma\n\nlust crossed out = Don't go after lusts of eyes\n\n9 Now my son, I would that ye should repent and forsake your sins, and go no more after the lusts of your eyes, but cross yourself in all these things; for except ye do this ye can in nowise inherit the kingdom of God. Oh, remember, and take it upon you, and cross yourself in these things.",
    "category": "Marriage and Family",
    "id": 15
  },
  {
    "question": "Wickedness never was happiness",
    "book": "BofM",
    "answer": "Alma 41:10\n\nOwl for Owlma \n\nWicked Owlma not happy\n\n10 Do not suppose, because it has been spoken concerning restoration, that ye shall be restored from sin to happiness. Behold, I say unto you, wickedness never was happiness.",
    "category": "Commandments",
    "id": 16
  },
  {
    "question": "Build your foundation on Christ.",
    "book": "BofM",
    "answer": "Helaman 5:12\n\nDoctor for Heal A Man\n\nHis hand for 5\n\nThe rock is Christ\n\n12 And now, my sons, remember, remember that it is upon the rock of our Redeemer, who is Christ, the Son of God, that ye must build your foundation; that when the devil shall send forth his mighty winds, yea, his shafts in the whirlwind, yea, when all his hail and his mighty storm shall beat upon you, it shall have no power over you to drag you down to the gulf of misery and endless wo, because of the rock upon which ye are built, which is a sure foundation, a foundation whereon if men build they cannot fall.",
    "category": "The Atonement of Jesus Christ",
    "id": 17
  },
  {
    "question": "Jesus Christ suffered the will of the Father in all things.",
    "book": "BofM",
    "answer": "3 Nephi 11:10-11\n\n3 Nephites humbly grateful that Christ suffered (hands scarred) the will of the Father\n\n10 Behold, I am Jesus Christ, whom the prophets testified shall come into the world.\n\n11 And behold, I am the light and the life of the world; and I have drunk out of that bitter cup which the Father hath given me, and have glorified the Father in taking upon me the sins of the world, in the which I have suffered the will of the Father in all things from the beginning.",
    "category": "The Godhead",
    "id": 18
  },
  {
    "question": "Jesus Christ invites us to become perfect",
    "book": "BofM",
    "answer": "3 Nephi 12:48\n\n3 Nephites like the Father and the Son\n\n12 allow for a perfect square\n\n48 Therefore I would that ye should be perfect even as I, or your Father who is in heaven is perfect.",
    "category": "The Godhead",
    "id": 19
  },
  {
    "question": "Watch and pray always in the name of Jesus Christ",
    "book": "BofM",
    "answer": "3 Nephi 18:15, 20-21\n\n3 Nephites praying\n\n18 year old missionary with Christ's name on him\n\n15 Verily, verily, I say unto you, ye must watch and pray always, lest ye be tempted by the devil, and ye be led away captive by him.\n\n20 And whatsoever ye shall ask the Father in my name, which is right, believing that ye shall receive, behold it shall be given unto you.\n\n21 Pray in your families unto the Father, always in my name, that your wives and your children may be blessed.",
    "category": "The Godhead",
    "id": 20
  },
  {
    "question": "Be baptized and sanctified by receiving the Holy Ghost",
    "book": "BofM",
    "answer": "3 Nephi 27:20\n\n3 Nephites have repented, were baptized and received the Holy Ghost, they are sanctified (clean) to stand spotless before God\n\n20 Now this is the commandment: Repent, all ye ends of the earth, and come unto me and be baptized in my name, that ye may be sanctified by the reception of the Holy Ghost, that ye may stand spotless before me at the last day.",
    "category": "Ordinances and Covenants",
    "id": 21
  },
  {
    "question": "A witness comes after the trial of faith",
    "book": "BofM",
    "answer": "Ether 12:6\n\nEther eggs\n\nDozen = 12\n\nMallet for witness after faith is tried\n\nNotice \"faith\" on the Mallet\n\n6 And now, I, Moroni, would speak somewhat concerning these things; I would show unto the world that faith is things which are hoped for and not seen; wherefore, dispute not because ye see not, for ye receive no witness until after the trial of your faith.",
    "category": "Acquiring Spiritual Knowledge",
    "id": 22
  },
  {
    "question": "The Savior can make weak things strong",
    "book": "BofM",
    "answer": "Ether 12:27\n\nEther eggs \n\nA dozen eggs for Ether 12\n\nWeak guy (skinny right arm) made strong (buff left arm)\n\n27 And if men come unto me I will show unto them their weakness. I give unto men weakness that they may be humble; and my grace is sufficient for all men that humble themselves before me; for if they humble themselves before me, and have faith in me, then will I make weak things become strong unto them.",
    "category": "The Atonement of Jesus Christ",
    "id": 23
  },
  {
    "question": "Charity is the pure love of Christ",
    "book": "BofM",
    "answer": "Moroni 7:45, 47-48\n\nGold angel = Moroni\n\n7 words \"Charity is the pure love of Christ\"\n\n45 And charity suffereth long, and is kind, and envieth not, and is not puffed up, seeketh not her own, is not easily provoked, thinketh no evil, and rejoiceth not in iniquity but rejoiceth in the truth, beareth all things, believeth all things, hopeth all things, endureth all things.\n\n47 But charity is the pure love of Christ, and it endureth forever; and whoso is found possessed of it at the last day, it shall be well with him.\n\n48 Wherefore, my beloved brethren, pray unto the Father with all the energy of heart, that ye may be filled with this love, which he hath bestowed upon all who are true followers of his Son, Jesus Christ; that ye may become the sons of God; that when he shall appear we shall be like him, for we shall see him as he is; that we may have this hope; that we may be purified even as he is pure. Amen.",
    "category": "Commandments",
    "id": 24
  },
  {
    "question": "The Holy Ghost reveals truth to those who ask God with real intent.",
    "book": "BofM",
    "answer": "Moroni 10:4-5\n\nAngel Moroni for Moroni\n\n10 fingers praying if the book is true\n\n4 And when ye shall receive these things, I would exhort you that ye would ask God, the Eternal Father, in the name of Christ, if these things are not true; and if ye shall ask with a sincere heart, with real intent, having faith in Christ, he will manifest the truth of it unto you, by the power of the Holy Ghost.\n\n5 And by the power of the Holy Ghost ye may know the truth of all things.",
    "category": "Acquiring Spiritual Knowledge",
    "id": 25
  },
  {
    "question": "In the First Vision, God called Joseph Smith to be a prophet.\nD&C Year (in PofGP)",
    "book": "PofGP",
    "answer": "Joseph Smith-History 1:15-20\n\nJoseph Smith's First Vision",
    "category": "The Restoration",
    "id": 26
  },
  {
    "question": "The voice of the Lord and His servants is the same.",
    "book": "D&C",
    "answer": "D&C 1:37-38\n\nThe Savior and his prophets are \"one\" for section 1.\n\n37 Search these commandments, for they are true and faithful, and the prophecies and promises which are in them shall all be fulfilled.\n\n38 What I the Lord have spoken, I have spoken, and I excuse not myself; and though the heavens and the earth pass away, my word shall not pass away, but shall all be fulfilled, whether by mine own voice or by the voice of my servants, it is the same.",
    "category": "Prophets and Revelation",
    "id": 27
  },
  {
    "question": "The only true and living church",
    "book": "D&C",
    "answer": "D&C 1:30\n\nThe only true and living church is #1\n\n30 And also those to whom these commandments were given, might have power to lay the foundation of this church, and to bring it forth out of obscurity and out of darkness, the only true and living church upon the face of the whole earth, with which I, the Lord, am well pleased, speaking unto the church collectively and not individually-",
    "category": "The Restoration",
    "id": 28
  },
  {
    "question": "Look unto Christ in every thought",
    "book": "D&C",
    "answer": "D&C 6:36\n\nThe eye for \"look\"\n\nThe Savior is the thought\n\n36 Look unto me in every thought; doubt not, fear not.",
    "category": "Acquiring Spiritual Knowledge",
    "id": 29
  },
  {
    "question": "The Holy Ghost speaks to our minds and hearts.",
    "book": "D&C",
    "answer": "D&C 8:2-3\n\nBrain = mind\n\nHeart = heart\n\n2 Yea, behold, I will tell you in your mind and in your heart, by the Holy Ghost, which shall come upon you and which shall dwell in your heart.\n\n3 Now, behold, this is the spirit of revelation; behold, this is the spirit by which Moses brought the children of Israel through the Red Sea on dry ground.",
    "category": "Acquiring Spiritual Knowledge",
    "id": 30
  }
]
